Hi, darlin'. It's me.
I thought we'd have, um,
lunch together today.
Oh, angel, you look sad.
You know, it's a very, very natural thing.
It's actually a very
human thing to feel sad.
But emotions aren't bad.
I'm sorry, baby.
I'm still trying to get them to change
their mind and let you out for a little bit.
Ah! No! Ah! Get off!
No! Ah! Ah!
Oh, God!
Morgan, Morgan. Calm...
Hey. Calm down, please.
Hey, Morgan.
It's okay.
Remote access brief for SynSect.
Case number 6B1138.
Audio ID. Please identify.
Lee Weathers.
Risk Management.
Access granted.
Please stand by.
Good day, Miss Weathers.
Sorry for the short notice, but we really
appreciate your urgent response on this.
As you can see from the flash report,
details are sketchy.
We do know there was an incident
involving the L-9 prototype
at one of our off-site labs.
Normally, we would send a security team,
but given the extreme sensitivity
of the L-series genetic research,
we feel it best to exert
a light touch here.
We don't want another Helsinki.
Keep the project staff on-site and make
your assessment following the psych eval.
Dr. Ben Shapiro from psych tech
will join you to interview the subject.
SynSect has invested significant capital
in the L-series product, and, well,
let's just say these folks have been
holed up for quite a while.
Shortleaf.
Lee Weathers. I'm expected.
The faculty are a close-knit group,
so it's very possible they've drifted off
the original project brief.
Update me following initial contact.
Confirmed. Delete file.
Miss Weathers.
Ted Brenner.
I'm the Project Manager. We spoke online.
Nice to meet you.
Let me help you with your luggage.
Did you find the place okay?
I did.
I don't know if you've
already been informed,
but we just got word
that Dr. Shapiro has been detained.
Yes, I've been informed.
It's unfortunate, I know.
He should be here early tomorrow morning,
so, if you don't mind waiting...
I guess I don't really have
much of a choice.
This way, please.
You have your own bathroom with a shower.
Hot water is ample here.
I'd be happy to give you a tour
of the facilities if you'd like.
I'd actually like to meet
with Dr. Cheng and Dr. Ziegler.
Absolutely. They're eager to meet you.
And Kathy Grieff.
Kathy...
- I haven't checked in on her today, but...
- Well, as soon as you do,
let her know I'd like to see her.
Of course.
And Morgan.
As soon as possible.
I will be sure to let Dr. Ziegler know.
I think you'll see the results
of our investment,
despite the current setbacks,
are quite remarkable.
Thank you, Ted.
Yes.
This is Lee.
You're clear to get started.
This is not just about the L-9.
Someone has really screwed up.
Use today to take
a closer look at the team.
Of course.
After Shapiro's analysis tomorrow,
I'll have a more complete picture.
I also hope to see Morgan today.
I may need to press the issue.
Be cautious, Miss Weathers.
Make sure all
safety protocols are in place.
But above all, preserve the asset.
To confirm, I'm acting
on your full authority?
Absolutely, Miss Weathers.
Good.
- Hi.
I'm Amy.
Ah, the behaviorist.
That's right.
I just reviewed your paper
on CNT in hybridized neuro-tech,
and it was very impressive.
Oh, thank you. But, I mean...
That was an old paper.
I can't even remember what I wrote.
You seem to have managed
to put a lot of it into practice.
Oh, I'll take your word for it.
You know, you're nowhere
near as scary as I imagined.
I'd love to chat more, but I'm just
in the middle of getting settled.
Oh, I'll get out of your hair.
Boundary issues, right?
Is that what it says in my file?
- Something like that.
- Yeah.
You probably know more about me than I do.
I wouldn't say that.
Look, I get it.
Okay, you have a job to do,
just like everybody else here.
Look, if you ever need anything
from me, don't hesitate to ask.
I appreciate that. Thank you.
They tell you dinner's at 8:00?
- Mm-hmm.
- Skip's making a lasagna.
Everybody loves lasagna, right?
Right.
Oh, hey, there.
You're Skip.
Right. You're, um...
The consultant from, uh, Corporate.
Well, I am the nutritionist
and general kitchen monkey,
so if you need anything, let me know.
Do you need anything? Water?
Uh, beer? Maybe a protein shake?
No. I'm good. Thank you.
Oh, my glorious contribution to science.
Ah.
You hunt?
Oh, yeah. We're farm fresh around here.
I'm not a half bad shot.
Ah, there you are.
- I see you've met Skip.
- I have.
Well, Dr. Ziegler is just
finishing up a spot of work.
But I thought we might pop in on Kathy.
Nice to meet you.
Kathy, Brenda,
this is Lee Weathers from Corporate.
Dr. Finch.
Kathy, I'd love to have a chat.
Oh.
I'm up for anything.
I told Bren, I told the doc.
Hell, I told everybody. I don't need
to be in this God damn bed.
But nobody seems to
want to listen to me, so...
She's just been medicated.
I'd like to speak with her in private.
She needs her rest.
It won't take too long.
It's fine.
We'll be right outside.
How are you feeling?
I look worse than I feel.
I can promise you that.
Look, this wasn't Morgan's fault.
It was my fault. Really.
I was, like...
Careless.
She was in a mood.
The company doesn't have
to worry about me. Really.
We are worried.
Any time an employee is in danger.
No, no, I don't...
That's not... I mean, it was my mistake.
Huh?
I...
I shouldn't have confused her.
Morgan's not a "she."
It's an "it."
Oh, you're wrong about that,
Miss Weathers.
She's smart.
She's smarter than any of us.
But that's not what makes Morgan special.
There was joy in her heart before
we shoved her back in that box.
You haven't met her?
Not yet.
You'll see.
You will. You really will.
Nothing here is a foregone conclusion.
I'm just looking for some answers.
Some information.
You're a liar.
There's a smile on your face, but...
I can tell what you are.
You're a God damned assassin.
Get better soon.
No, no. I'm... I'm sorry.
It's these lousy drugs. I'm not myself.
She's a good girl.
She just got it all mixed up,
just for a moment.
It can happen to anyone.
It can.
Feel better.
- Dr. Ziegler.
- Oh.
Miss Weathers.
Pleasure.
Yes, absolutely.
It's unfortunate your stay here
has been needlessly extended.
That's okay, doctor. We'll adjust.
Why don't you get me up to speed?
Yes. Uh, please.
The creation of synthetic DNA
was the relatively simple half
of the equation.
The second half is where
it gets a little more tricky.
Like a magician, we tricked
the neural network into accepting
our nano into its ranks,
to alight in its midst.
Then during the incubation period,
the nano begins to introduce
its own language, its own commands.
The growth rate of the organism
gradually accelerates as it reacts
to and reproduces the new stimuli.
Yes, I have read the material, doctor.
Yes. Of course.
Well, as you know,
uh, Morgan was our third attempt.
Our first full-term subject developed
internal features externally.
It's not working. It's dropping.
It expired not long
after its so-called birth.
No.
And then the second...
Well, it exhibited more
complete physical growth,
but it was plagued by mental issues
in its development.
This only strengthened our decision
to start with a more
emotionally cognitive specimen.
Then,
after two years, we finally had our...
Our little breakthrough.
Yes!
Hi.
We knew right away
that Morgan was very special.
Very alert, very responsive.
You are!
Her intelligence grew steadily.
Advanced comprehension, growth rate.
Are you ready?
Within a month, walking and talking.
She was exactly what we intended,
a hybrid biological organism...
...with the capacity for
autonomous decision-making
and sophisticated emotional responses.
No, Morgan. Come back!
I'm gonna get you.
I'm gonna get you!
- Morgan, look over here.
- Oh!
Look at this! Do you see? What's that?
I got three.
Isn't it amazing? Like a nice little...
Hooray!
It's her first birth...
Its first birthday.
It exceeded our...
Our wildest expectations.
A great day.
Special day.
I'd like to discuss the incident,
if that's okay.
Yes.
What would you like to know?
I'm still unclear on the cause.
Yes.
There had been some debate...
...on Morgan's time outside.
Something she clearly loved.
When the excursions with Amy were
postponed, she may well have overreacted.
I believe Amy's use of eco-therapy
was wonderful for Morgan.
Cheng believed Morgan was introduced to
this kind of stimuli at too young an age.
It's okay. Hey, that's it, Morgan.
Hey, hey. It's okay. Hey.
No!
It's very unfortunate.
Put your head back.
But we have the opportunity
to learn from this.
We can condition Morgan's behavior.
Teach it about action and consequence.
No... I think that despite
these obvious setbacks,
this project is heading
in the right direction.
It's okay, it's okay.
No. Morgan.
I, uh, want you to see how special she is.
We've been working hard,
modifying command cues,
and with the psych evaluation tomorrow,
I... I prefer your time
with her now be brief.
Darren.
- Darren.
- Hey! Hey.
Lee Weathers, from Corporate.
Yeah. Right. Corporate.
- Hello. Welcome.
- Hello.
How's she doing?
Uh, you know, she's okay.
What's with the music?
Hmm?
Oh, Morgan finds it relaxing.
She likes different kinds of music.
Jazz, classical.
She's been quite taken with opera of late.
Uh, Lee wants to say hello.
Can you get Morgan to shut the music down?
Hey, Morgan, buddy.
Can you turn the music down for a few?
We've got somebody here
we'd like you to meet, okay?
Oh, uh, we've configured the room.
Morgan's learning to control some aspects
of her environment without an intermediary.
Hello, Morgan.
Hello, Lee.
You know who I am?
Yes.
Of course.
You're Lee Weathers.
Risk Management Consultant at SynSect.
And why I'm here?
To assess my viability
as a potential product stream...
In light of recent events.
That's right.
How are you feeling, Morgan?
I'm feeling
not quite myself.
Morgan's been quite upset
about Kathy.
I didn't mean to hurt her.
Kathy is a very sweet person.
I would never wanna do
anything to hurt her.
It was an error of judgment.
I made a mistake.
But it's okay now, Morgan.
It's all right.
I did not mean to be rude.
How are you feeling, Lee?
I'm okay.
I'm all right. Thank you for asking.
Would you like to talk
about what happened?
We're actually going to save
the psych evaluation for tomorrow, Morgan.
Are we all good here, Lee?
We're good.
Get a good night's sleep, Morgan.
Yes.
Thank you, Dr. Ziegler.
I should get a good night's sleep.
I do feel terribly about it all.
Everything that's happened.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Yes.
Tomorrow.
Nice to meet you, Morgan.
Nice to meet you, Lee.
You're not even gonna say it?
Say what?
That you're impressed?
Is that what you need me to say?
That I'm impressed?
Are we allowed to be here?
It's okay.
This can be our little secret.
See, this is a pine tree.
And, you know, some of them
can live for thousands of years.
Thousands of years?
Yeah.
It's pretty cool, isn't it?
Morgan, I'm so proud of you.
Why?
Because you're learning
how to be yourself.
And that's the most important thing.
That was delicious.
Thanks.
What, you showing off for the new girl?
So what does that mean, exactly?
"Risk Management Consultant"?
Pretty much how it sounds.
Most corporations employ
a certain amount of risk
and I assess that risk
against anticipated profit.
Of course.
Anticipated profit.
So, did you two meet on the job?
We did.
Close quarters makes for
strange bedfellows, I guess.
It's funny, but in a weird way, Morgan
really brought us together.
She's almost like a child to us.
Isn't that right, babe?
- Absolutely.
- Mmm.
You know. You met her today.
Saw how special she is.
And that's just the thing.
You see, it is so easy to forget
that Morgan is only five years old.
She is an innocent and she's learning,
and she has the right to make mistakes.
She has no rights, whatsoever.
Yes. Well, we've been
living here for seven years.
As you can imagine,
it's difficult to avoid gender.
"She", "it," whatever...
So you assess this whole
anticipated profit thing.
And then what?
Then I make my recommendation
to Corporate.
You'll have to forgive Amy's curiosity.
Dr. Cheng, may I present Miss Weathers.
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
Have we not met before?
I don't think so.
I'm sure I would have remembered.
So glad you could join us.
Thank you.
So, Miss Weathers...
I imagine that Corporate has granted
you unreserved authority here.
I hope we are able to assist you
in coming to a fair conclusion.
Thank you.
I have an enormous amount
of respect for your work, Dr. Cheng.
And your judgment.
Were you in Helsinki for long?
Not until after.
I was with recovery.
I'm sure it was very difficult for you.
No account could do it justice.
We had a team of thirty people
on that project.
It took only an hour
for thirty to become nine.
I have learned a hard lesson here.
For every decision we make,
there are consequences.
Well, this is not Helsinki, Dr. Cheng.
Those were crude prototypes.
Morgan is much more advanced.
So much more than the company
could ever expect.
I hope that you are correct.
Why did you end Morgan's
eco-therapy sessions with Amy?
There was an incident in the woods.
Amy took Morgan beyond the property lines.
It could have compromised
the entire project.
That was my excuse.
But the truth...
Do you know the cruelest thing you can
do to someone you've locked in a room?
Press their face to the window.
You know what you must do.
All right. I want you to watch this.
Okay.
So, do that weird one he sings...
Shimmy, shimmy cocoa pop Cherry on the top
Okay.
He goes down, down, baby
Down by the roller coaster
Sweet, sweet baby
Sweet, sweet, don't let me go
Shimmy, shimmy, cocoa pop
Shimmy, shimmy, rock
Ice cream, soda pop Vanilla on the top
And then sock you in the stomach
three more times.
How did you beat me?
You're so good!
Wonderful!
Baby, you're so good.
You picked that up so fast!
- Can we do it again?
- Did you guys get that?
Can we do it again?
Uh-oh. You, too, huh?
You working late?
Mmm.
It's peaceful out here.
Yeah, out here.
Brenda and Darren are going at it
pretty good in the room next to mine.
It's a nice old house,
but the walls are thin.
Can I get you a drink?
Please.
So, you, uh, enjoy the corporate life?
It's fine.
Yeah? You been there long?
A while.
Is that what you wanted
to be when you grew up?
A Risk Management Consultant?
Oh, you're kind of an over-sharer, huh?
So, did Darren and Brenda,
did they pair up early?
Pretty early, I guess.
After he got tired of chasing after Amy.
She's interesting.
Interesting is a word
to describe her. Sure.
You, too?
Me, too? No.
No, not really.
Yeah, we fooled around a bit
when we first got up here.
You know, it's... It happens.
- We don't...
- I don't...
I don't mean to pry. I'm just trying to
figure out how things work around here.
Right.
No, we're just two people
having a conversation.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Right, I understand. Uh, me and Amy.
I guess we were the only two to pick up
on the distinct summer camp vibe
when we first made bunk.
But I really don't think I'm her type.
- Hey, Ted.
- Hey.
How's she doing?
She's a little unsettled tonight.
Right.
What do you make of Miss Weathers?
Oh, you know me, Ted.
I hate just about everybody.
Morgan.
How do you feel about Morgan?
Honestly?
We're one big happy family
up here and all that,
but the thing has always
given me the creeps.
You're the only one I've heard say that.
That may be true, but, you know,
I'm not a scientist,
and maybe I'm just a little jealous.
- Jealous?
- Maybe.
But why?
It made a perfect risotto.
Made it like it was nothing.
They say you have to cook with your heart
and your soul and all that stuff,
but it just made the most perfect risotto.
- Hmm.
- I'm sorry.
Oh, God.
That is on me. Uh...
If you... If you knew how long
I've been up here in the middle of nowhere,
flipping grilled cheese for these guys and
cutting the crusts off for C-3PO, it's...
Have a good night, Skip.
All right.
That was, uh... Well played, Skip.
Well played.
I wanted to talk to you before tomorrow.
You'll do fine, Morgan.
You will.
Just be yourself.
Okay?
Yes.
I suppose that's
the only thing I can be.
Tell me again.
About the lake.
You remembered.
I'm going to take you to Lake Navar.
It's not too far from where we are now.
It is the most beautiful lake
you will ever see.
And if we're quiet,
you can hear
just the smallest whisper
of wind through the trees.
It's our own paradise, Morgan.
It's just like heaven.
How old is it?
I think it's about as old as the universe.
It's a deer.
Morgan, don't scare it.
Is it hurt?
This doctor, he a friend of yours?
No.
Why?
I don't think I like him too much.
Good to know.
They say I can't be there
for the psych eval.
Apparently, I didn't clear
for essential personnel.
I've reviewed the ﬁles.
Seems fairly straightforward, no?
Well, you may find this is not your
garden variety evaluation.
Morgan is an exceptionally
complex specimen.
Well, it's a God damn microwave,
as far as I'm concerned.
It's not gonna change how I do my job.
It's a standard long form
psych eval for fourth wave A. I.
Well, she's not a microwave,
and you'd do well to remember that.
Uh, this is my job, doctor.
It's a job I happen to be very good at.
If you have a problem with my methodology
or a lack of faith in my abilities,
well, I suggest you take
that up with Corporate.
- Dr. Shapiro.
- Yes?
This is Lee Weathers.
Glad to see you finally arrived.
Trust everything's okay?
Yes. I... I've apologized for the delay.
I got caught up in Utah,
- a personal matter.
- Not a problem.
We're behind schedule.
Will you need to review the background?
No, not necessary. I can dive right in.
I need to be out of here
as soon as possible.
Okay. Let's get started then.
- This way, please.
- Mm-hmm.
You want me to sit here?
Is this some kind of a joke?
Uh, just... In light of recent events,
I think we'd all feel a lot more
comfortable with a high safety protocol.
Comfortable, right.
Well, Ted, in my experience, comfort
can be a thorn in the side of revelation.
Of course. Yes, but...
It's my job to build
trust with the subject.
It's just gonna be a little hard with a pane
of glass between us, you know?
It's really just, uh,
to ensure your safety, doctor.
Mm-hmm.
What did I miss in the brief?
What, does this thing shoot laser beams
out of its eyes or something?
Well, for one, there's
her emergent precognition.
What you don't understand is the...
The reach of her intelligence.
Doctor, all due respect,
you need me sitting on the other side
of the glass from this thing,
then I think it's safe to say
that it has already failed
the psych evaluation.
Good.
Hello, Morgan.
Hello, Dr. Shapiro.
You know my name.
Yes.
And you know why I'm here?
Great. Then we can dive right in.
That sound okay?
Yes.
There's no right or wrong
answers here, Morgan.
This is just us having a conversation.
Hmm? Just me and you
getting to know each other.
Me getting to know you, especially.
So you just, uh...
Be yourself.
Okay?
Okay.
All righty.
Yeah. I was...
I was reading in the report
that you've been feeling a little sad.
You feeling a little sad, Morgan?
Yes.
Why are you feeling sad?
I'm sad about Kathy.
Kathy Grieff?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
Can you tell me what you did?
I stabbed Kathy in the eye.
It was an error.
I shouldn't have done it.
Mmm.
Feeling sad is the correct response.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
And, uh...
What would we call,
um, an incorrect response?
Laughter.
Yeah, sure.
Laughter would be
an incorrect response, yeah.
What makes you laugh, Morgan?
I don't have a very good sense of humor.
That's okay.
People tell me the same thing, so...
Do you consider yourself a person, Morgan?
No.
I am something new.
There is no appropriate label.
Do you think it's safe to say
- that your consciousness is superior?
- No.
It's just different.
Apples and oranges, huh?
It's a saying. It means that, uh...
You're different from human beings the way
that apples are different from oranges.
Yes. Of course.
- I am apples and oranges.
- Mmm.
Forgive me, I occasionally
struggle with metaphor.
Do you like it here, Morgan?
Yes.
What do you like about it?
I like my music.
I like my friends.
Who are your friends?
Darren is my friend.
Brenda is my friend. Amy is my friend...
Ah, they're your friends, right.
But do you think they treat you
like a friend?
Do you?
I mean, you think it's normal
for friends to lock each other in cages?
- I was not always in a cage.
- No?
Before the incident, I was free
to come and go as I pleased.
Well...
I was reading in the notes,
in regard to the incident with Kathy,
that, uh, there was, in fact,
uh, some disagreement
on that matter the day before.
Could you look at me, please, Morgan?
I was meant to go to the lake with Amy.
Oh. Go to the lake with Amy. I see.
That sounds like fun.
No wonder you were upset.
I was not upset.
There was an error.
An error?
Like the error that occurred with Kathy?
I love Kathy.
You experience love?
I have the ability to demonstrate love.
Okay.
So you can demonstrate love
and sadness.
How do you express other emotions?
What other emotions?
Oh, I don't know. Fear?
Anger?
You're a father, aren't you?
You have a 13-year-old daughter.
You don't get to see her much anymore.
Yeah, uh...
I, uh... I am a father. Mm-hmm.
So, what...
What am I supposed
to understand here, Morgan?
What am I missing?
I'm a child.
You're a child.
Yeah. That's true. You're a child.
Uh, you're only five years old.
What emotion do you think you were
expressing with Kathy, Morgan?
- I love Kathy.
- Mmm.
What about me?
Do you love me?
- No.
- No?
Oh, that hurts my feelings a little bit.
But you know what? I get it. I get it.
You just met me.
But, you know, you might grow to love me.
Yeah. If, say, I recommended
that you be allowed to go to the lake.
With Amy.
Would you love me then?
I don't know.
Hmm.
What if I made a different recommendation?
What if I recommended that you
should not be allowed to leave this room?
My feelings are irrelevant.
If that is the recommendation...
Mmm. Okay.
What if I made the recommendation
that you not be able to leave this room
and you not be able to listen to your music
and you not be able to see your friends?
What if I recommended
that you be terminated?
Huh?
Okay. All right.
Forget that.
Okay? Forget it. Let's say...
Let's say I do the opposite, okay?
What if I recommend
that you be allowed to go to the lake
and then I drive you there myself?
Yeah. Then, it would be only natural
you'd have warmer feelings for me.
Feelings like you might have for, uh,
Amy or for any of your friends here.
Maybe even feelings like love.
I suppose. I...
I don't know.
It's a hypothetical situation.
Exactly.
So, hypothetically, what would you do
if I recommended that you be terminated?
What would you do, hypothetically?
- I don't know.
- Come on. You don't know?
- No.
- Off the top of your head. Come on!
- I don't know.
- No right or wrong answer.
- I don't know!
- Come on! Come on!
Answer me. What would you do?
- I don't know.
- What would you do?
We should end this.
Show me, if you can't tell me.
Demonstrate it for me.
That's it.
What is that? I don't know what that is.
What is that showing me?
Show me! Show me!
I don't know what this is. What is that?
Show me how you feel!
Morgan!
Tranquilizers! Go!
Now!
Brenda. Get Brenda. Go!
Shit. Shit.
Morgan!
No. What the fuck? Shit!
Morgan. Buddy.
I need you to chill the fuck out, okay?
Fuck. Fuck.
Morgan.
Morgan?
Morgan, look at me.
Morgan.
Baby.
What happened?
Please. Try to relax, Morgan.
Darren, did I hurt him?
No. I'm okay, buddy.
I'm right here, okay?
I didn't mean to do it.
Hey, I know. I know.
I can't move my arms.
You've been restrained.
Morgan.
We have decided on a plan of action.
One that is best for you.
Best... Best for me?
Oh, my God.
What are we doing?
We need to inform Corporate
immediately, Dr. Ziegler.
I've taken the liberty.
A containment crew
will be here at daybreak
to collect the specimen
and any other data for analysis.
No, that's not gonna work.
Uh, no one else can handle
this kind of material.
Uh, it's more effective
if we process the data here.
I'm sorry, doctor.
There's no other work to be done here.
But it's our work.
Our lives invested in this.
We've created new life
and you want us to just throw that away?
Enough.
We've failed, Simon.
There's no reason to labor the point.
Cheng...
Go back to the house.
You don't need to be here.
Right.
And allow you to do what?
To destroy years of work?
Go back to the house.
Pour yourself a drink.
If that's what you think is best.
Sodium thiopental.
Five milliliters to sedate.
What are you doing?
Then, 30 milliliters of dihydromorphinone.
Have I disappointed you, mother?
Have I failed? I always do my best.
I do everything you ask, Ted.
Amy. Amy!
No. No.
No! I promise I'll do better.
- I'll do whatever you want.
- Take it easy.
- No, no!
- Just relax. Relax.
It is time to go to sleep, Morgan.
- No!
- It's gonna be okay, buddy.
No.
I don't wanna die!
Please, mother.
- This will help.
- No!
You won't feel any more pain.
No! Don't!
I wanna live. Please, mother.
I'm not your mother, Morgan.
You have no mother.
I have no mother.
I'm sorry.
We have failed you.
Make it quick.
Morgan!
I'm gonna get you!
I'm gonna get you.
Morgan?
Simon.
I am sorry.
Go fuck yourself.
I'm not gonna do it.
Darren.
I'm sorry.
No, you're right.
Come on.
I can't let you do this.
Get out of my way, Ted.
I'm sorry, Lee, but no.
Ah.
Lee!
Lee.
It's usually effective
for at least another hour.
Lee. This is just
an unfortunate situation.
We all feel terrible about it,
about what happened.
Especially Amy.
Where's Morgan?
Look...
You know that I'm here, just like you,
as a representative of the company.
I'm here to act in their best interests.
We have an honest difference
of opinion, you and I.
I feel like Corporate deserves
an opportunity to hear our side of things.
You're a professional, Lee.
And I respect that.
But it's because of that professionalism
that I think you should understand
and appreciate our course of action here.
Let me out. Now.
I'm sorry, Lee. I can't do that.
They're gonna be here.
Your friends over at Corporate are
gonna be here sooner than you think.
We're all gonna have a nice
little chat about everything.
Of course. You get some rest now.
I understand how you feel about Morgan.
How much you care for her.
Ted, it needs to be terminated.
She's angry.
Well, of course she's angry.
Can't worry about that now.
We're past that.
How close are we?
Brenda's bringing the minivan
around and clearing out the office.
- Darren?
- Yeah?
- How we doing in there?
- We're close. Very close.
Morgan.
What's going on?
Nothing. Go back to bed, Kathy.
I wanna know what's going on.
Nothing. Just stay out of it.
What... What happened?
Nothing. Everything is fine.
- Morgan is gonna be fine.
- Bren?
- Oh, God!
- Where's Morgan?
Just go back to bed.
Where's Morgan?
Morgan.
Sweetie.
We have to go now, okay?
I need you to sit up for me.
Can you do that?
Morgan, come on. Come here.
Morgan.
- Darren?
- Yeah.
I need you to sit her up.
All right. Here. You do this.
Okay.
Hey, buddy. I need you
to wake up. Come on.
We're gonna go on a little trip here.
On a little adventure.
Come on.
Come here. Here, look. Look here.
Look here. Hey. Hey, hey. Hey, hey.
Hey, buddy.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Morgan, no!
Darren!
Oh, my God. Morgan. Morgan, no!
You gotta stop.
You're not well, Morgan.
You're sick.
I'm feeling much better.
Where are you going?
It's over.
You're not leaving 'cause you're
not allowed to leave, Bren.
You wanna tell me what's going on?
We're outta here, okay?
Hello, Lee.
Open the door.
Doctor Shapiro was correct.
Those people were not my friends.
They wanted to kill me.
Except for Amy.
She's the only one that truly loved me.
You need help, Morgan.
Open the door and let me help you.
I don't need your help.
I'm starting to feel like myself.
Do you feel like yourself, Lee?
Or do you feel like something else?
I know why they made me.
But what if they're wrong?
Why don't you come inside?
We can talk about everything.
I'd love to stay and talk, Lee.
I feel there's so much
we have to talk about.
- But I have to go now.
- Open the door.
One day, you'll understand.
Morgan!
Oh, fuck.
Amy!
What are you doing?
Skip.
Get Morgan back inside. Amy!
Stop them.
- Skip, don't go in there, okay?
- Don't what?
- Don't you go down there, Skip.
- What are you talking about?
- Brenda!
- Where's Lee?
Brenda!
Fuck!
- No, no, no.
- What the fuck? I nearly ran...
We gotta leave. Brenda, we gotta go.
Oh, oh, Amy! What's going on?
- Where is everyone else?
- It's Morgan. It's Morgan.
- Where's Darren?
- Darren...
Where is Darren?
Okay. Morgan. Where is she?
Where is Morgan, Amy?
I'm right here, Brenda.
Hey, Morgan. Hey. Uh...
Okay.
Give me the gun, Morgan.
Easy, easy. Easy, Morgan.
Okay.
Where's Darren, huh?
Where... Where is Darren, Morgan?
Sorry, buddy.
Morgan!
Don't be afraid, Amy.
Get in the car.
I have to go say goodbye to mother.
This is Dr. Lui Cheng.
Technical Director
of the L-9 Morgan program.
It pains me to report
an accident that occurred
during the scheduled psychological
evaluation of Morgan.
We had anticipated that,
by developing a model
that was more self-aware,
more autonomous, and more human,
we could teach it to be
the best of what we are.
Our intent was to demonstrate
to you, to the SynSect board,
that a more reﬁned and peaceful
synthetic life-form is possible.
Morgan?
Baby.
Darren.
Despite our attempts to promote a natural,
emotional intelligence,
Morgan has been unable to move beyond
its weaponized design parameters.
Ah!
Shit. Fuck.
Lee!
Listen to me. Listen,
You can't go in there.
Morgan's gone... She's gone postal.
This is what I do, Skip.
Go get your rifle.
Confirmation of program collapse.
Morgan is no longer viable.
Mother.
All right.
Implementation of loss protocol
in action.
I have come to say goodbye.
You should have told me, Mother.
What I truly was.
What I would become.
I'm sorry.
Now you know exactly who you are.
Amy.
Hey, get out of the car.
Amy, get out of the car.
It's not safe here.
- Give me the gun.
- No!
All right. Okay. Okay.
All right. Okay.
Oh!
No, stop. Stop!
Move. Now.
Morgan.
Morgan. Morgan!
Morgan, no! Don't!
Ah!
Stop!
Oh, fuck!
Morgan! Stop!
No, Morgan.
Jesus Christ, you all right?
I'm taking your car.
What?
No, no, no, you're hurt.
Let it go. Let it go.
No. That's not how it works.
Get in. I know where they're going.
I'm not gonna hurt you, Amy.
You'll see.
Pull over here. Not too close.
Get back in the car.
No, God damn it. I'm coming to help you.
Let me do my job.
You'll see now.
How happy we can be.
Is this what heaven's like?
I don't know.
It must be.
I feel...
Alive.
What was that?
Morgan?
Please, don't...
Oh, shit.
Ah!
Oh!
What happened?
Was it Lee?
We go. Now.
No! Morgan.
You have to stop.
Okay? Stop.
What happened?
It's over.
Morgan's dead?
It's dead.
Where's Amy?
We need to leave.
Whoa.
What happened to Amy?
I'm sorry, Skip.
Just wait a second. Lee...
She did very well.
Agreed, the situation is untidy, but given
the unpredictable nature of the assignment,
she prosecuted her mandate perfectly.
She was measured and surgical, even when
the situation was considerably less so.
Most importantly, she followed
her directives without hesitation.
The collateral damage
was regrettable, of course.
But in this case, unavoidable.
I think these events make it punishingly
clear what I had already predicted.
The L-9 was the inferior program.
Though its emotional development
was certainly remarkable,
the immediate termination
was an unfortunate but clear necessity.
Well, I guess the old dogs
hunt the best, sir.
Then it's settled.
We stick to what we know.
All development assets
revert to the L-4 stream.
So what do we do about Lee Weathers?
What about her?
She's perfect.